Contact

matheusfinatto2@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ matheusfinatto (LinkedIn) github.com/MatheusFinatto (Portfolio)

Top Skills

React.js

Node.js

TypeScript

Languages

Inglês (Full Professional)
Português (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Nodejs: Crie uma API Rest padronizada e escalável

HTTP: Entendendo a web por baixo dos panos

Rest com Nodejs: Api com Express e Mysql

The Web Developer Bootcamp 2022 React do Zero a Maestria (c/ hooks, router, API, Projetos)

Matheus Finatto

Software Developer at Wonder Sistemas

Erechim, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

Summary

Hello, my name is Matheus Finatto!

I am a web developer with some experience working with React.

I am also a Computer Science student, currently in my 5th out of 8 semesters, and hold a Bachelor's degree in Business Administration. I have an advanced level of English.

My main focus is on React development, but I am always excited to learn new things!

On my GitHub profile, you can see some of my personal projects, such as a movie library using React and the TMDB API, a responsive website made with HTML and CSS, and a game library that uses the IGDB API and was developed in collaboration with three other students on a college project.

(Visit: https://github.com/MatheusFinatto to see much more!)

In addition to React, some of my favorite technologies include TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python, Node.js, Express.js, and Flask.

If you want to know more about me, feel free to get in touch!

INTJ-A Personality - MBTI®

Experience

Wonder Sistemas Software Developer October 2022 - Present (8 months) Erechim, Rio Grande do Sul, Brasil

As a web tools developer for an ERP software, I specialize in utilizing cuttingedge technologies such as React, GraphQL, Apollo GraphQL, and Ant Design. My key responsibilities include:

- Designing and implementing web-based solutions that seamlessly integrate with our ERP system
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams
- Utilizing React and Ant Design to develop intuitive and responsive user interfaces that enhance user experience
- Leveraging GraphQL and Apollo GraphQL to develop efficient and reliable data-driven applications that improve system performance

Compass.uol

Chatbot Take Intern

December 2021 - March 2022 (4 months)

Erechim, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

Learning related to Javascript, Node.js, Blip chatbot platform, IBM Watson Assistant and other tools for making chatbots and integrations with APIs.

Finatto Incorporadora e Engenharia

Administrative Analyst

March 2020 - December 2021 (1 year 10 months)

Erechim, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

Maintenance of social media, online sales announcements, development of floor plans in AutoCAD, other activities related to the transition of real estate.

MyClub

8 months

Management Analyst

November 2019 - February 2020 (4 months)

Erechim, Rio Grande do Sul

Technical support to partner companies;

Manual testing of the application before releasing updates;

Support in managerial decision-making, applying strategic planning methods and

troubleshooting such as PDCA cycle and 5W2H;

Business Administration Intern

July 2019 - November 2019 (5 months)

Erechim, Rio Grande do Sul

Conducting a supervised internship for completing an undergraduate course, based on the mapping of sales processes; Monitoring of organizational

processes and their mapping; Suggestions for improvements based on the literature in the area of organizational processes

Education

Universidade Regional Integrada do Alto Uruguai e das Missões - URI

Bacharelado, Ciência da Computação · (February 2021 - December 2024)

Universidade Federal de Santa Maria Bacharelado, Administração · (2016 - 2020)